Zahraa Alaaeddine

Beirut, Lebanon | zahraaalaedine@gmail.com | +961 76 939 206 LinkedIn | Github

PROFILE

I'm a Linguistics graduate specialising in Computational Linguistics. I'm well-versed with both aspects of web development - front and back.My distinct approach and enthusiasm for creative problem-solving position me as a valuable leader keen to contribute to the success of the web development team.

EXPERIENCE

Codi-Tech, Beirut | *Full-Stack Web Development*

August 2023- PRESENT

- Used various Backend technologies including Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, MySQL, PhpMyAdmin,
 SQLite, Postman API
- Developed the Frontend of several projects using various libraries and frameworks such as React.js,
 Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) and saas, JavaScript
- Worked on administering and maintaining the server hardware and software using Linux.

Codi-Tech, Beirut | Scrum Master

August 2023- PRESENT

Employed the Agile methodology of project management to plan, organise, and optimise workflow, ensuring successful project completion and client satisfaction.

EDUCATION

Lebanese University, Faculty of Linguistics, Beirut

Bachelor's degree in Computational Linguistics | October 2020-June 2023

Thesis: Analysing Sentiment in Social Media Data Using Machine Learning Techniques.

TECH SKILLS

Frontend: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, TypeScript | Design Skills: Figma, Canva

Backend: Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Sequelize | **Tools:** Visual Studio Code, Postman

Database: Mongoose, Xampp

Version Control: GitHub

RESTful API Design and Integration

Responsive Web Design

PROJECTS

E-Commerce Website | React, Node.js, Express, and MongoDB.

• Developed a fully functional e-commerce website with CRUD functionality using MERN stack(MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js).

Python Teaching Website | HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.

• Led the development of a Python teaching website during university, merging a passion for programming with a commitment to education. The website stands as a source of pride, with the potential to positively impact aspiring programmers and learners.

Digital Wallet and Payments Application | React, Node.js, Express, Sequelize, and XAMPP

- Led the end-to-end development of a sophisticated Digital Wallet and Payments Application using the Sequelize ORM and XAMPP stack.
- Implemented CRUD functionality to enhance user interactions and system operations.

AWARDS

Member in the EdTech Syndicate in Lebanon EdTechS

LANGUAGES

Arabic (native); English (Proficient Level)